hello everyone my name is Greg and I Dev
stuff welcome everyone to episode 23 of
tactics gaming Unity elevation and
Status panel
severe elevation difference limit we
have an elevation on our map but it
doesn't affect the movement of the
character on the map our character can
climb any elevation level without any
problem like this
so we want to take into account the
elevation when we are moving around
open pass finding
inside calculate walkable nodes we need
to take into account the elevation
so go and create a new method on our
grid map called check elevation
we need to pass our position of the node
we are moving from
and to the node we are moving towards
in this method return false means we
can't move into this node because of
severe elevation difference
so call continue
create a new method and open it
inside we need to get the elevation of
node where moving from an elevation of
the node we are moving into
now we need to calculate the elevation
difference between those two points
subtract the elevation of the node we
are moving out from the elevation of the
node we are moving in
we have elevation difference now so
let's compare it against the new
parameter called character climb the
higher these numbers has the elevation
our character can climb or descend
towards the elevation difference in
absolute number this will allow us to
make comparison even if the number is
negative
meaning the slope is descending down
then check if character clamp is bigger
than elevation difference
good
as you can see skip slopes can be
climbed but lower slopes can be you need
to make sure to design them up around
this feature like if you have similar
looking cube with very steep descent you
should avoid using it in places where
you expect your character to be able to
climb on top of it or climb down so make
it tall enough even if for example in
this case you can see that the cube is
very steep but character can already
climb it you better to shape your map to
accommodate the possibility of climbing
this slope by easier making it into a
natural heal or introducing some kind of
structure like ladder so the climb would
look more natural the safest is brought
to you by generous support of people on
patreon and members on YouTube if you
want to join them link to my patreon in
the description and join button
available right now on YouTube
let's start making status panel which
will show you the stats of the character
so when you hover over the character you
want to show a panel these
characteristics of the character create
panel for status panel
create text for character name
create and add a new component to the
game manager called status panel
open the newly created script
we already have system in place for
detecting hover over character so cachet
now when we hover over the character we
want to show the status panel otherwise
if there is no character we want to hide
it use is active pool variable
if it is active is false we check if
hover over character is not new meaning
there is someone we are hovering over
this means we should show the panel
if active is true meaning we're already
showing status panel for someone we are
checking if hover over character is null
meaning we moved our Mouse somewhere
else to a different position and we are
not hovering over anyone anymore and we
don't need to show off the panel anymore
this should be enough to show and hide
the panel in the editor reference status
panel and hide the panel
good
so now let's show Name the character on
the screen so create and call a new
method called update status when you
show the panel
inside use whole hover over character to
get his name and display it on the
screen
this should be enough to just display
character name
let's change the name of the second girl
Warrior
there is an issue that our character
status is not updating if they stand
close enough if we switch between
characters like this the characters who
is adjusted to each other the status
panel is not updating
this is happening because we are
updating our panel only the moment we
show it to the player so when the two
characters stand adjusted to each other
we are not reassuring the panel to the
player once again
and because of that it's not updating
the status of the panel so to make it
work we need to check if the character
we are currently hovering over is not
the same character we showed the status
panel 4.
so saves the reference to the character
we're currently hovering over
when status panel is active check is the
character where hovering over is not the
same as we keep referencing in status
panel
then update the reference to the current
character status who is showing and
updates the status panel
Let's test this
error returned out of the executions
okay let's test this
good this is it for this episode if you
have any questions or any ideas about
code please leave your comment below if
you want to support further link to my
patreon in the description special thank
you to this old hash do for his generous
support with best regards see in the
next episode